Hi,I'm Martí Mas and in collaboration with
DXC Technology,
we are presenting the roject "Tuning
a Generative Language Model for the C
reation of Customized Chatbots for Pu
blic Administrationssupervised by
Josep Suy.
We built a system that gives a L
arge Language Model access to databases
or websites and is customizable to client
needs through BPMNs using Flowable. The
databases or websites
provided by the clients contain
up-to-date information. The system can
answer user queries truthfully by
augmenting the model's ability to
generate text with the ability to
retrieve information from these databases
or websites.
Retrieval is done intelligently by
finding the most semantically relevant
pieces of information in the database.
With this system, we avoid hallucinations
while allowing for a wide range of
possible configurations different clients
might require.
This is called the Retrieval Augmented
Generationor RAG. We implement
a custom RAG solution called Small-T
o-Big-Retrieval which is able to query
the documents from multiple semantic
levels at the same time.
On the frontend, for accessibility
reasons, we deploy on edge machine
learning to perform hotword recognition
on the user's machine. This is done on
edge for privacy reasons as we don't want
to constantly send microphone data to the
cloud. Chatbot.
Using machine learning, we first classify
user queries into two categories, hard
ones and easy ones. We then choose to use
a larger or a smaller Language Model to
answer the queries based on this
classification, reducing costs. This is
called RouteLLM.
We also implement measures to restrict
the behavior of language models to stick
to their stakeholders needs and
guidelines.
The system refuses to answer questions
outside the scope defined by the
stakeholders or questions that might
abuse the system.
Here's a quick demo of how it all
comes together. Here a
stakeholder , the "Departament de Drets Socials
de la Generalitat" wants to help citizens
know how social rights work and what
social benefits
they might have access to. The system
asks a few questions to understand the
user's situation and recommends possible
benefits that might be available to them.
Thank you for your attention.